Contact

jeffreyneuberger918@gmail.c

www.linkedin.com/in/jeffreyneuberger-5265b2221 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

PHP

Vue.js

JavaScript

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Jeffrey Neuberger

Senior PHP/JavaScript Developer Bellmore

Summary

I am a passionate and seasoned full-stack web developer with 8+ years of experience, including 4 years of a senior web developer at Icreon, one of New York's leading IT companies. In the past, I have designed and programmed websites for internal and external use, along with JavaScript-based responsive/dynamic web applications, using React, Vue, Angular, Node, Express, and various database. I have developed many PHP 7.x | 8.x / Laravel 5.x | 6 lts | 7.x based websites, providing support with content-based requests, custom forms, back-end (Laravel, Symfony, Yii, Codelgniter), and front-end (Vue, Svelte, TailwindCSS, Materialize, React, Angular).

- Experiment and keep the toolchains and frameworks updated and current.
- Recommending tooling updates as well as pitching newer and more efficient technology.
- Experience in building toolchains for developing front-end applications using both JavaScript and TypeScript.
- Deep knowledge of building SPA applications using frameworks like Vue, Svelte, etc. as well as server-composed applications.
- Knowledge of a popular CSS framework like Bootstrap, Materialize, Foundations, etc.
- Full proficiency in writing semantic, standards-compliant HTML and CSS.

Experience

Icreon

Senior Web Developer (Laravel, Vue, React, Node) 2018 - 2021 (3 years) Buffalo, NY

 Pioneered the first comprehensive Vue static site generation framework in the Deno ecosystem for creating scalable Vue applications that can be transformed into minified rendered pages for improved SEO and deployability

- Wrote a memoized recursive algorithm to traverse Vue.js' component dependency tree, optimize build performance, and generate components in the appropriate reference order
- Created a comprehensive CLI to walk developers through the initial setup of a Vno SSG boilerplate application

Plus972

Full-stack Web Developer (Laravel, Yii, Symfony, Vue, Angular, React) 2015 - 2017 (2 years)

New York, NY, United States

- Incorporated WebSockets to implement a dev server with a live-reload feature by monitoring file changes and transmitting updates to the browser to provide prompt feedback for the developer in real-time
- Used Deno libraries to develop a custom component parser that asynchronously loads props from data-fetching hooks, increasing reusability of page-level components and allowing flexibility in injecting dynamic content
- Utilizing Next.js, designed and developed a product and documentation website with optimized page load performance and web searchability through server-side rendering
- Leveraged Next.js native hooks and syntax to create modularized components and dynamically routed pages

Website Depot Inc. Digital Marketing & SEO Web Developer (PHP, Laravel, Vue, Angular) 2013 - 2014 (1 year)

New York, NY, United States

New York, NY

- Employed Laravel, Redux and local storage for state management, to engineer a tutorial-based documentation application
- Containerized Vno's web application using Docker to offer a scalable, operating-system agnostic, lightweight, and consistent development solution
- Deployed via AWS's Elastic Beanstalk to employ its ability to scale services based on the needs of the application, as well as, the ease in which it enables deployment with minimal overhead costs

GreyBox Creative Software Engineer (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) January 2012 - December 2012 (1 year) New York, NY, United States

- Design, involved in code reviews and wrote unit tests in PHP and Updated site with Laravel, JavaScript, JQuery, Yii, Symfony, and SQL.
- Implemented user interface guidelines and standards throughout the development and maintenance of the Website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and VueJs.

Education

New York University

Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Science · (2006 - 2011)